ISTVAN GERCSAK

ADDRESS: Apartment 48, The Pine, Winter Garden, Pearse Street, Dublin 2

Phone: +353894473833

e-mail: istvan.gercsak@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/istvangercsak/ GitHub account: https://github.com/IstvanGercsak

SUMMARY:

I am highly engaged to my profession with my 5 years of experience in the software testing field. I like to do it and I always want to be better therefore I committed next to self-improvement. My experiences stands for manual and automation testing, proved work experience in agile environment, basic programming skills, wide-spreaded technical and business knowledge.

COMPUTER SKILLS:

BDD(Cucumber), CI, ISTQB-CTFL, Java, JavaScript, Junit, Jenkins, Agile development (Scrum), Selenium Webdriver with Java, SQL, Putty, Test automation, TestNG, Version control, XML and JSON syntax, Ongoing Full Stack Developer Diploma

WORK EXPERIENCE:

14/05/2019 - Present

OpenJaw Technologies, QA Automation Engineer, Ireland

(OpenJaw Technologies provide solutions for the global flight industry all around the world.)

- QA responsibilities:
 - I work with two Developer teams
 - I use Jira for Bug tracking and write test scenarios
 - o I collaborate with other teams (DevOps team, Architect team)
- Test Automation responsibilities:
 - o I create new Test Automation framework
 - I create Test Automation Analysis document
 - I create pilot project from scratch
 - Used stack: Maven, Gauge, Selenium, Java
- Manager responsibilities:
 - I interview the new QA candidates
 - I report the QA side to the costumer in every week about the actual process
 - I introduce the ongoing QA tasks and give update during the weekly team meetings

10/2017 - 29/03/2019

MetLife, Test Consultant (Contractor), Ireland

(Our project was an insurance payment tracking system. It was an experimental project and it was created from scratch thus it is changing a lot)

- Design manual test cases in BDD format and execute them
- Find bugs in the software and report it in Jira
- Interact with the business analyst, test lead and the developers to discuss and resolve the defects
- GUI Test automation pilot:
 - GitHub (I created a repository)
 - Jenkins (I created a Jenkins servers. The jobs triggered by the commits)
 - o Cucumber (Cucumber business cases, Cucumber report)
 - TestNG (As testing framework, TestNG reports)
 - o Selenium Webdriver with Java

05/2016 - 08/2017

IP Systems Ltd., QA Test Engineer, Hungary

(The IP Systems Ltd. operates in the energy market, mostly in the gas and electricity field. It develops IT platforms for the participant of the market depends on the customer needs. The products are very wide-spreaded)

- Functional testing web based software
- · Communication with the costumers and the Product Owner
- Ensure the quality of the actual projects (with tests and advises):
 - Energy Data Clearing House (6 months)
 - Multidimensional auction system (3 months)
 - Trading-IP (5 months)
- Prepare test environments:
 - Build test environment with Jenkins jobs
 - Prepare the test environment to test (upload date, prepare test cases, check the log files)
- Managing release processes
- Participation every steps of the SDLC
 - Sprint planning and Scrum meetings
 - Supervise the release process
- Write automation tests (Selenium WebDriver (Java)) (only one of my 3 months long project)

01/2016 - 05/2016

Aegon Hungary Composite Insurance Company Ltd., Junior IT Business Analyst, Hungary

- Writing functional specifications and user guides
- Supervising the daily and monthly closure
- · Assistance with the satellite systems
- Cooperation with the programmers

05/2014 - 12/2015

Aegon Hungary Composite Insurance Company Ltd., Junior Tester, Hungary

(The Aegon insurance company is one of the biggest insurance company in Hungary. Its CRM system handles the life and non-life insurance contracts. Its software used by the insured people and administrators as well.)

- Manual testing the business processes in the CRM insurance portfolio systems
- Maintain & Support the actual systems and projects
- Handling the incoming error tickets (prioritization, management)
- Working closely with the developers and the business analysts.
- Participate more projects as tester

EDUCATION:

2019

- 01/2019 Present
 - Full Stack Software Development Diploma (Code Insitute Bootcamp)
 - <u>Technologies</u>: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Git & GitHub, JavaScript, jQuery, Jasmine, API, TDD, Python, Flask, Data Management, SQL, Mongo DB, Agile development

2018

- ISTQB Advanced Level Automation Test Engineer Course
- ISTQB Advanced Level Test Manager Course
- Online courses belongs to the test automation:
 - Selenium Webdriver with Java Basics to Advanced
 - Cucumber with Selenium Java (Basic)

2016

- ISTQB-Foundation level certification

2011 - 2014

- University of Debrecen, Debrecen, Hungary
 - o Business Informatics Bachelor Degree